Some legends will never be forgotten. Some wrongs can never be forgiven.
Unforgiven is a western film directed by Clint Eastwood.
William Munny is a retired, once-ruthless killer
turned gentle widower and hog farmer.
To help support his two motherless children, he accepts one last
bounty-hunter mission to find the men who brutalized a prostitute.
Joined by his former partner and a cocky
greenhorn, he takes on a corrupt sheriff.
William Munny, played by Clint Eastwood.
'Little' Bill Daggett, played by Gene Hackman.
Ned Logan, played by Morgan Freeman.
The Schofield Kid, played by Jaimz Woolvett.
English Bob, played by Richard Harris.
W.W. Beauchamp, played by Saul Rubinek.
Unforgiven is a 1992 American revisionist Western film produced and directed
by Clint Eastwood from a screenplay by David Webb Peoples.
It stars Eastwood as William Munny, an aging outlaw and killer who
takes on one more job years after he turned to farming.
The film co-stars Gene Hackman, Morgan Freeman, and Richard Harris.
Unforgiven premiered at the Mann Bruin Theater on August 3,
1992 before being released by Warner Bros.
on August 7, 1992.
It grossed over $159 million on a budget of $14.4 million and received widespread critical acclaim, with praise for
the acting (particularly from Eastwood and Hackman), directing, editing, themes, and cinematography.
The film won four Academy Awards: Best Picture, Best Director for Eastwood, Best
Supporting Actor for Hackman, and Best Film Editing for Joel Cox.
Eastwood was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Actor for his
performance, but lost to Al Pacino for Scent of a Woman.
The film was the third Western to win Best Picture, following
Cimarron (1931) and Dances With Wolves (1990).
Eastwood dedicated the film (at the end of the credits) to directors and
mentors Sergio Leone and Don Siegel; "Dedicated to Sergio and Don".
In 2004, Unforgiven was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being deemed "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film was remade into a 2013 Japanese film, also titled Unforgiven, which stars
Ken Watanabe and changes the setting to the early Meiji era in Japan.
Eastwood has long asserted that the film would be his last traditional Western, concerned that any
future projects would simply rehash previous plotlines or imitate someone else's work.
The film explores themes of prostitute, sheriff,
right and justice, regret, wyoming, usa.
The tone is dark.